oceansafety.com 2019-07-05

# Ocean Safety Ltd - Privacy Policy

## BACKGROUND:

Ocean Safety understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used and shared online. We respect and value the privacy of everyone who visits this website, www.oceansafety.com (“Our Site”) and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a manner that is consistent with Our obligations and your rights under the law.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of Our Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of Our Site. If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Our Site immediately.

## 1\. Definitions and Interpretation

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:  
“Account”  means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Our Site;

“Cookie” means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Our Site when you visit certain parts of Our Site and/or when you use certain features of Our Site. Details of the Cookies used by Our Site are set out in section 13, below;  
“personal data” means any and all data that relates to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from that data. In this case, it means personal data that you give to Us via Our Site. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)  
“We/Us/Our” means Ocean Safety, a limited company registered in England under company number 02880054, whose registered address is Ocean Safety, Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF, and whose main trading address is Ocean Safety, Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF.

## 2\. Information About Us

2.1 Our Site is owned and operated by Ocean Safety, a limited company registered in England under company number 02880054, whose registered address is Ocean Safety, Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF and whose main trading address is Ocean Safety, Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF.  
2.2 Our VAT number is GB 787 4360 87.  
2.3 Our Data Compliance Officer is Alistair Hackett, and can be contacted by email at [ahackett@oceansafety.com](mailto:ahackett@3sisafety.com), by telephone on 02380 720801, or by post at Ocean Safety, Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF.  
2.4 We are regulated by the Marine Coast Guard Agency, Lloyd’s Registry, the Transport of Pressure Equipment Directive (TPED) and First Point Assessment (FPAL) under the scope of ISO 9001:2008.  
2.5 We are a member of British Marine Federation.

## 3\. What Does This Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy applies to your use of Our Site and all personal data held by Ocean Safety Limited. Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that We have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and We advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

## 4\. Your Rights

4.1 As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR, which this Policy and Our use of personal data have been designed to uphold:  
4.1.1 The right to be informed about Our collection and use of personal data;  
4.1.2 The right of access to the personal data We hold about you (see section 12);  
4.1.3 The right to rectification if any personal data We hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete (please contact Us using the details in section 14);  
4.1.4 The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask Us to delete any personal data We hold about you (We only hold your personal data for a limited time, as explained in section 6 but if you would like Us to delete it sooner, please contact Us using the details in section 14);  
4.1.5 The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;  
4.1.6 The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);  
4.1.7 The right to object to Us using your personal data for particular purposes; and  
4.1.8 Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.  
4.2 If you have any cause for complaint about Our use of your personal data, please contact Us using the details provided in section 14 and We will do Our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK’s supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner’s Office.  
4.3 For further information about your rights, please contact the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

## 5\. What Data Do We Collect?

Depending upon your use of Our Site, we may collect some or all of the following personal and non-personal data (please also see section 13 on Our use of Cookies and similar technologies):  
5.1 name;  
5.2 date of birth;  
5.3 gender;  
5.4 business/company name  
5.5 job title;  
5.6 profession;  
5.7 contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers;  
5.8 demographic information such as post code, preferences, and interests;  
5.9 financial information such as credit / debit card numbers;  
5.10 IP address;  
5.11 web browser type and version;  
5.12 operating system;  
5.13 a list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on Our Site, and the site you exit to;

## 6\. How Do We Use Your Data?

6.1 All personal data is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with Our obligations and safeguard your rights under GDPR at all times. For more details on security see section 7, below.  
6.2 Our use of your personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for Our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to Our use of your personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails), or because it is in Our legitimate interests. Specifically, we may use your data for the following purposes:  
6.2.1 Providing and managing your Account;  
6.2.2 Providing and managing your access to Our Site;  
6.2.3 Personalising and tailoring your experience on Our Site;  
6.2.4 Supplying Our products and/or services to you (please note that We require your personal data in order to enter into a contract with you);  
6.2.5 Personalising and tailoring Our products and/or services for you;  
6.2.6 Replying to emails from you;  
6.2.7 Supplying you with emails/post/SMS that you have opted into (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time by pressing the unsubscribe button at the bottom of any emails received from Ocean Safety;  
6.2.8 Market research  
6.3 With your permission and/or where permitted by law, we may also use your data for marketing purposes which may include contacting you by email, telephone, SMS or post with information, news and offers on our products and/or services. We will not, however, send you any unsolicited marketing or spam and will take all reasonable steps to ensure that we fully protect your rights and comply with Our obligations under GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.  
6.4 You have the right to withdraw your consent to Us using your personal data at any time, and to request that We delete it.  
6.5 We do not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. Data will therefore be retained for the following periods (or its retention will be determined on the following bases):  
6.5.1 For financial reasons, some data will be kept for 6 years + 1, to meet compliance objectives. From a safety compliance in a regulated industry, we are compelled to keep some details for up to 10 years. For Marketing purposes, we will keep your details for 5 years, at which point we will contact to update your details and preferences. After these dates thresholds are exceeded, the data will be purged within 3 months.

## 7\. How and Where Do We Store Your Data?

7.1 We only keep your personal data for as long as We need to in order to use it as described above in section 6, and/or for as long as We have your permission to keep it.  
7.2 Some or all of your data may be stored outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using Our Site and submitting information to Us. If We do store data outside the EEA, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under GDPR including:  
7.2.1 Aside from marketing automation platform and an email marketing service none of our 3rd party suppliers hold data outside of the EEA. In the event we contact you via agents such as Mailchimp and SurveyMonkey we first ensure their compliance to GDPR regulations and also gain your consent before contacting you.  
7.3 Data security is very important to Us, and to protect your data We have taken suitable measures to safeguard and secure data collected through Our Site.  
7.4 Steps We take to secure and protect your data include:  
7.4.1 We use GDPR compliant suppliers. This means that your personal data will be fully protected under the GDPR or to equivalent standards by law.

## 8\. Do We Share Your Data?

8.1 We may share your data with other companies in Our group for safety reasons only or when we are obliged to for legal reasons. This includes Our subsidiaries and/or Our holding company and its subsidiaries.  
8.2 We may sometimes contract with third parties to supply products and services to you on Our behalf. These may include payment processing, delivery of goods, search engine facilities, advertising, and marketing. In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, Our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under the law.  
8.3 We may compile statistics about the use of Our Site including data on traffic,  
usage patterns, user numbers, sales, and other information. All such data will be anonymised and will not include any personally identifying data, or any anonymised data that can be combined with other data and used to identify you. We may from time to time share such data with third parties such as prospective investors, affiliates, partners, and advertisers. Data will only be shared and used within the bounds of the law.  
8.4 We may sometimes use third party data processors that are located outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”) (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). Where We transfer any personal data outside the EEA, we will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under GDPR including:  
8.4.1 MailChimp, SurveyMonkey, Nest Forms. We ensure your data is secure by periodically checking they are compliant with GDPR regulations;  
8.5 In certain circumstances, We may be legally required to share certain data held by Us, which may include your personal data, for example, where We are involved in legal proceedings, where We are complying with legal requirements, a court order, or a governmental authority.

## 9\. What Happens If Our Business Changes Hands?

9.1 We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business. Any personal data that you have provided will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business that is being transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Privacy Policy, be permitted to use that data only for the same purposes for which it was originally collected by Us.  
9.2 In the event that any of your data is to be transferred in such a manner, you will not be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.

## 10\. How Can You Control Your Data?

10.1 When you submit personal data via Our Site, you may be given options to restrict Our use of your data. In particular, We aim to give you strong controls on Our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from Us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in Our emails and at the point of providing your details and by managing your Account).  
10.2 You may also wish to sign up to one or more of the preference services operating in the UK: The Telephone Preference Service (“the TPS”), the Corporate Telephone Preference Service (“the CTPS”), and the Mailing Preference Service (“the MPS”). These may help to prevent you receiving unsolicited marketing. Please note, however, that these services will not prevent you from receiving marketing communications that you have consented to receiving.

## 11\. Your Right to Withhold Information

11.1 You may access certain areas of Our Site without providing any data at all.

## 12\. How Can You Access Your Data?

You have the right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Under the GDPR, no fee is payable and We will provide any and all information in response to your request free of charge. Please contact Us for more details at osinfo@oceansafety.com or use the contact details below in section 14.  
If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown in Part 14. If we do hold information about you, we will:  
• Give you a description of it  
• Tell you why we are holding it  
• Tell you who it could be disclosed to  
• Let you have a copy of the information

12.1 No fee is payable under normal circumstances. We reserve the right to charge a reasonable fee for requests that are manifestly unfounded, excessive, or repetitive. Such charged will be based only on the administrative cost that we will incur in order to respond. 

## 13\. Our Use of Cookies

13.1 Our Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer or device. First party Cookies are those placed directly by Us and are used only by Us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve Our products and/or services. We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure that your privacy and personal data is protected and respected at all times.  
13.2 All Cookies used by and on Our Site are used in accordance with current Cookie Law.  
13.3 Certain features of Our Site depend on Cookies to function. Cookie Law deems these Cookies to be “strictly necessary”. These Cookies are shown below in section 13.5. Your consent will not be sought to place these Cookies, but it is still important that you are aware of them. You may still block these Cookies by changing your internet browser’s settings as detailed below in section 13.6, but please be aware that Our Site may not work properly if you do so. We have taken great care to ensure that your privacy is not at risk by allowing them.  
13.4 In addition to the controls that We provide, you can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. Most internet browsers also enable you to choose whether you wish to disable all Cookies or only third party Cookies. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser or the documentation that came with your device.  
13.5 You can choose to delete Cookies on your computer or device at any time, however you may lose any information that enables you to access Our Site more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, login and personalisation settings.  
13.6 Our Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on your computer or device. First party Cookies are those placed directly by Us and are used only by Us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Our Site and to provide and improve Our products and/or services.

## 14\. Contacting Us

If you have any questions about Our Site or this Privacy Policy, please contact Us by email at [osinfo@oceansafety.com](http://oceansafety.com/privacy-policy#link_tab), by telephone on 02380 720801, or by post at Ocean Safety Ltd , Saxon Wharf, Lower York Street, Southampton, SO14 5QF, UK. Please ensure that your query is clear, particularly if it is a request for information about the data We hold about you (as under section 12, above).

## 15\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time (for example, if the law changes). Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date
